<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">ResourcesTest_GB</string>
    <string name="language">English</string>
    <string name="density" translatable="false" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">DPI</string>
    <string name="orientation">Portland</string>
    <string name="night_mode">Not night</string>
    <string name="screen_format">Not long</string>
    <string name="version" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation">Any</string>
    <string name="descriptionLanguage">Language</string>
    <string name="descriptionDensity">Density</string>
    <string name="descriptionOrientation">Orientation</string>
    <string name="descriptionNight_mode">Night mode</string>
    <string name="descriptionScreen_format">Screen format</string>
    <string name="descriptionVersion">Version</string>
    <string name="version_pic">Your Version\n(click to show other version)</string>
    <string name="version_name">Version name</string>
    <string name="endl_rus">Endl/Rus</string>
    <string name="descriptions">Descriptions!</string>

    <string-array name="version_name">
        <item>About Android</item>
        <item>Android 1.5 Cupcake</item>
        <item>Android 1.6 Donut</item>
        <item>Android 2.0 Eclair</item>
        <item>Android 2.2 Froyo</item>
        <item>Android 2.3 GingerGread</item>
        <item>Android 3.0 Honeycomb</item>
        <item>Android 4.0 Ice Cream Sandwich</item>
        <item>Android 4.1 Jelly Beam</item>
        <item>Android 4.4 KitKat</item>
        <item>Android 5.0 Lollipop</item>
        <item>Android 6.0 Marshmallow</item>
        <item>Android 7.0 Nougat</item>
        <item>Android 8.0 Oreo</item>
        <item>Android 9.0 Pie</item>
        <item>Android 10.0 </item>
        <item>Android 11.0 </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="version_description_en">
        <item>
            Android OS was launched in November 2007 and the first commercial smartphone based on
            the same came a year later by HTC the HTC Dream, which was released in select markets.
            The OS that started with just a single device in 2007 now powers billions of smartphones,
            tablets, and other smart devices and is currently the most used mobile operating system
            across the world. The very first version of Android was called as Android 1.0, which was
            also known as Android Alpha, then came its successor Android 1.1 or Android Beta.
            From then on up until the Android 10 release, every Android version was launched in a
            dessert name as the Android versions were a bit confusing. Here is the complete detail
            on every Android version launched to date.
        </item>

<!--        <item>-->
<!--            Android 1.0 is the very first iteration of Android with an application programming-->
<!--            interface 1 or API 1. It was released on September 23, 2008, and officially there was-->
<!--            no code name for this version but according to some reports, it was known as Android Alpha.-->
<!--        </item>-->

<!--        <item>-->
<!--            Android 1.1 also did not get any official code name and as per reports, it was known as-->
<!--            Android Beta, released on February 9, 2009, with API 2. Android 1.1 introduced features-->
<!--            like support for third-party keyboards, video recording, video playback, and copy-paste-->
<!--            feature for the web browser.-->
<!--        </item>-->

        <item>
            Android 1.5 was released on April 27, 2009, and it is the first Android version to
            officially get a dessert nickname. Android 1.5 was known as Android Cupcake and it was
            developed by Google with API 3.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 1.6 Donut was released on September 15, 2009, just a few months after the launch
            of the Android 1.5 Cupcake and it came with the API 4. This was also called the fourth
            version of the Android and it introduced some distinctive features such as support for
            CDMA technology, support for different screen sizes, and a battery usage indicator that
            was also first introduced on this version.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.0 Eclairs came with an API level of 5 to 7 and it was released on October 26 2009,
            again, a fourth major Android update to get released in 2009. The fifth version of Android
            aka the Android 2.0 Eclair offered features like an improved UI with a Google search bar
            on the top and it also supported HTML 5.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.2 Froyo was made available to the public on May 20, 2010, and it came with API 8.
            This version was unveiled during Google I/O 2010 conference and it offered several
            optimizations when compared to Android 2.0 Eclairs.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.3 Gingerbread was also launched in 2010, to be exact on December 6, 2010,
            with API 9 to 10. This version introduced features like NFC support and VoIP calls.
            The Nexus S smartphone from Samsung was the first device to launch with this OS,
            which was also the first Nexus smartphone from Google that represented stock Android OS.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 3.0 Honeycomb was released on February 22, 2011, and it came with API 11 to 13.
            This version of Android was designed for large screen devices like tablets and the
            Motorola Xoom was the first product to ship with Android 3.0 Honeycomb.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.0 Ice Cream Sandwich was released on October 18, 2011, and it came with an API
            version from 14 to 15. This version was designed to offer a unified experience for both
            smartphones and tablets. It was also the first Android version to support Face Unlock on
            select devices.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.1 Jelly Bean got official on July 9, 2012, and it came with an API of 16 to 18.
            Android Jelly Bean is also officially the 10th iteration of Android and it was developed
            to offer performance improvements along with smooth user experience when compared to
            Android 4.0.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.4 KitKat got official on October 31, 2013, and it came with an API of 19 to 20.
            This version of Android was developed to offer an improved user experience on devices
            with limited hardware capabilities.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 5.0 Lillipop offered a major design overhaul when compared to Android 4.4 KitKat
            and it was released on November 12, 2014, and it came with an API version of 20 to 22.
            This version of Android offered a redesigned UI and it also replaced Dalvik with ART or
            Android Runtime to improve application performance and battery optimization.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 6.0 Marshmallow was released on October 5, 2015, based on API 23. It offered a
            new permission architecture to improve user-privacy and it also natively supported USB
            Type-C port and a physical fingerprint sensor.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 7.0 Nougat with an API version of 24 to 25 was released on August 22, 2016.
            Nougat offered support for Vulkan API for better graphics rendering along with a new app
            notification format.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 8.0 Oreo got launched on August 21, 2017, and this version was based on API
            26 to 27. Oreo was the first Android version to support Bluetooth 5.0 and wide color gamut.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 9 Pie got official on August 6, 2018, with API 28 and it offered a refreshed
            material design with a new style of navigation buttons. Till today, a lot of smartphones
            are still based on Android 9 Pie.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 10 was released on September 3, 2019, based on API 29. This version was known as
            Android Q at the time of development and this is the first modern Android OS that does not
            have a dessert code name. It offered a complete full-screen user-interface with a redesigned
            navigation system, which is a bit similar to the modern iPhones.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 11 was released on September 8, 2020, and this version was based on API 30.
            It comes with features like conversation notifications and this is also the first official
            Android version to offer a built-in screen recorder.
        </item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="version_description_ru">
        <item>
           ОС Android была запущена в ноябре 2007 г. и стал первым коммерческим смартфоном на базе
             то же самое было сделано годом позже HTC, HTC Dream, который был выпущен на избранных рынках.
             Операционная система, которая началась с одного устройства в 2007 году, теперь поддерживает миллиарды смартфонов.
             планшеты и другие интеллектуальные устройства, и в настоящее время это самая используемая мобильная операционная система.
             по всему миру. Самая первая версия Android называлась Android 1.0, которая была
             также известный как Android Alpha, затем появился его преемник Android 1.1 или Android Beta.
             С тех пор до выпуска Android 10 каждая версия Android запускалась в
             название десерт, так как версии для Android были немного запутанными. Вот полная информация
             на каждой выпущенной на сегодняшний день версии Android.
        </item>

<!--        <item>-->
<!--            Android 1.0 - это самая первая итерация Android с прикладным программированием.-->
<!--             интерфейс 1 или API 1. Он был выпущен 23 сентября 2008 г. и официально-->
<!--             у этой версии нет кодового названия, но, по некоторым данным, она была известна как Android Alpha.-->
<!--        </item>-->

<!--        <item>-->
<!--            Android 1.1 также не получил официального кодового названия и, согласно отчетам, был известен как-->
<!--             Бета-версия Android, выпущенная 9 февраля 2009 г., с API 2. В Android 1.1 представлены функции-->
<!--             например, поддержка сторонних клавиатур, запись видео, воспроизведение видео и копирование и вставка-->
<!--             функция для веб-браузера.-->
<!--        </item>-->

        <item>
            Android 1.5 был выпущен 27 апреля 2009 г., и это первая версия Android,
             официально получить десертное прозвище. Android 1.5 был известен как Android Cupcake и был
             разработан Google с помощью API 3.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 1.6 Donut был выпущен 15 сентября 2009 года, всего через несколько месяцев после запуска.
             Android 1.5 Cupcake и поставлялся с API 4. Его также называли четвертым
             версия Android и представила некоторые отличительные особенности, такие как поддержка
             Технология CDMA, поддержка экранов разных размеров и индикатор заряда батареи,
             также впервые был представлен в этой версии.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.0 Eclairs поставляется с уровнем API от 5 до 7 и был выпущен 26 октября 2009 года.
             Опять же, четвертое крупное обновление Android, которое выйдет в 2009 году. Пятая версия Android
             он же Android 2.0 Eclair предлагает такие функции, как улучшенный пользовательский интерфейс с панелью поиска Google.
             вверху, а также поддерживает HTML 5.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.2 Froyo стал общедоступным 20 мая 2010 года и поставлялся с API 8.
             Эта версия была представлена на конференции Google I / O 2010 и предлагала несколько
             оптимизации по сравнению с Android 2.0 Eclairs.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 2.3 Gingerbread также был запущен в 2010 году, а именно 6 декабря 2010 года.
             с API 9–10. В этой версии представлены такие функции, как поддержка NFC и вызовы VoIP.
             Смартфон Nexus S от Samsung был первым устройством с этой ОС,
             который также был первым смартфоном Nexus от Google, который представлял собой стандартную ОС Android.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 3.0 Honeycomb был выпущен 22 февраля 2011 года и поставлялся с API 11–13.
             Эта версия Android была разработана для устройств с большим экраном, таких как планшеты и
             Motorola Xoom была первым продуктом, поставляемым с Android 3.0 Honeycomb.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.0 Ice Cream Sandwich был выпущен 18 октября 2011 года и поставлялся с API
             версия с 14 по 15. Эта версия была разработана, чтобы предложить единый интерфейс для обоих
             смартфоны и планшеты. Это также была первая версия Android с поддержкой Face Unlock на
             выберите устройства.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.1 Jelly Bean был официально представлен 9 июля 2012 года, и его API составлял от 16 до 18.
             Android Jelly Bean также официально является 10-й версией Android и был разработан
             чтобы предложить улучшения производительности наряду с плавным пользовательским интерфейсом
             по сравнению с Android 4.0.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 4.4 KitKat был официально представлен 31 октября 2013 года, и его API составлял от 19 до 20.
             Эта версия Android была разработана для улучшения взаимодействия с пользователем на устройствах.
             с ограниченными аппаратными возможностями.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 5.0 Lillipop претерпел серьезные изменения в дизайне по сравнению с Android 4.4 KitKat.
             и он был выпущен 12 ноября 2014 года, и у него была версия API от 20 до 22.
             Эта версия Android предлагала переработанный пользовательский интерфейс, а также заменяла
             Dalvik на ART или  Android Runtime для повышения производительности приложений и оптимизации
            заряда батареи.
        </item>

        <item>
           Android 6.0 Marshmallow был выпущен 5 октября 2015 года на основе API 23. Он предлагал
             новая архитектура разрешений для улучшения конфиденциальности пользователей, а также встроенная поддержка USB
             Порт Type-C и физический датчик отпечатков пальцев.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 7.0 Nougat с версией API от 24 до 25 был выпущен 22 августа 2016 года.
             Nougat предлагает поддержку Vulkan API для лучшего рендеринга графики вместе с новым приложением
             формат уведомления.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 8.0 Oreo был запущен 21 августа 2017 года, и эта версия была основана на API.
             С 26 по 27. Oreo была первой версией Android, поддерживающей Bluetooth 5.0 и широкую цветовую гамму.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 9 Pie был официально представлен 6 августа 2018 года с API 28 и предлагал обновленную версию
             материальный дизайн с новым стилем кнопок навигации. До сих пор очень много смартфонов
             по-прежнему основаны на Android 9 Pie.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 10 был выпущен 3 сентября 2019 года на основе API 29. Эта версия была известна как
             Android Q на момент разработки, и это первая современная ОС Android, которая не
             иметь кодовое название десерта. Он предлагал полный полноэкранный пользовательский интерфейс с переработанным
             система навигации, которая немного похожа на современные iPhone.
        </item>

        <item>
            Android 11 был выпущен 8 сентября 2020 года, и эта версия была основана на API 30.
             Он поставляется с такими функциями, как уведомления о разговорах, и это также первый официальный
             Версия для Android со встроенным устройством записи экрана.
        </item>
    </string-array>
</resources>